battle ropes are a unique form of
training that can be used to not only
improve your conditioning but also your
overall strength level now there's a lot
of battle ropes out there for you to buy
but I've got two great options from
living fit in the garage today the
canvas one and the braided one and guess
what I'm gonna break both of them down
for y'all
[Music]
what's up everyone it's Jake back in the
barbing garage gym with another review
ready to go for y'all this time around I
have two count them two battle ropes
from living fit I'm gonna break down for
you guys I'm gonna tell you everything
you need to know about both of these
ropes from the price the features some
pros and cons and of course who should
or should not add one of these to their
home gym now before I get going with all
that I gotta let you know we've reviewed
a ton of battle ropes on barbin.com so
if you want to browse our best list just
go and search barvin best battle ropes
and you can find out for yourself which
ones that we like the best
foreign
like about these battle ropes well
they're both 50 feet long which is
really nice it's going to allow you to
move up and down the rope and it's going
to in turn either make it easier or more
difficult on you depending on which
direction you decide to go in now they
both also feature rubber handles right
here it's going to allow you to get a
really solid grip as you're working out
both of these ropes are also really
durable specifically this canvas one
this is going to be great for outdoor
usage any type of texture flowing maybe
some artificial turf you might be
working out on but don't sleep on this
braided rope it's going to be more
durable than a triple strand rope is
it's going to last you a really long
time there's three different diameters
you can choose for your ropes to be and
you also receive a portable anchor with
your purchase
[Music]
all right now when it comes to the Cons
with these battle ropes there's really
only two things that I can think of
let's talk about the money first so the
cheapest option is going to run you
around 90 bucks or so and you know
there's a lot of cheaper ones available
on the market you can find some cheaper
ones on Amazon one thing is those
probably won't last you as long as these
will and second is the length of the
actual ropes so yeah having them be 50
feet long is a good thing but not
everybody has that amount of space so if
you're tight on Space you need a shorter
rope I suggest checking out some other
options
okay so let's expand on the money now
once again both of these ropes are
available in three different diameters
and that's going to impact the price so
let's talk about the braided rope first
this one and a half inch diameter we
have right here is going to run you
around 100 bucks the two inch option is
going to be around 140 and the three
inch option is going to be around 210 or
so now with the canvas rope every single
option is going to be around 10 or so
cheaper than the braided one so the one
and a half inch version we have right
here is right around 90 bucks the two
inch version is about 130 and the three
inch is going to cost you around 200
okay now compared to the rest of the
market you know pretty standard in terms
of pricing with these and you can't
really go wrong with either one of these
ropes right here but remember you know
if you're planning on doing your
workouts outside you're better off with
this canvas option because it's going to
last you longer I think it's gonna be
worth the money for anybody who's going
to be doing a lot of battle rope
training but if you're barely going to
be doing it I think you're gonna be
better off saving some money and you
know finding a cheaper option on Amazon
I found one for like 50 bucks and I mean
you can definitely take that route just
remember that's probably not going to
last you as long as these two will
[Music]
okay so let's talk about the build now
and some of the features with both of
these battle ropes now once again these
are 50 feet long it's going to be really
nice you can move up and down the rope
and make your workout harder or easier
so living fit uses a polydacter on rope
and if you don't know what that means
it's basically the most durable rope
that's available so that's obviously a
really nice thing I really like the
rubber grips right here just gives you a
nice solid grip as you're working out
okay so the actual weight of your rope
is going to be directly impacted by the
diameter that you're choosing and
remember both of these are available in
three different options one and a half
two inches and a three inch diameter so
both one and a half inch options weigh
28 pounds the two inch canvas weighs 38
pounds while the two inch braided rope
weighs 40 pounds the three inch canvas
rope weighs 88 pounds while the three
inch braided rope actually weighs 86
pounds
[Music]
all right so let's go and do a quick
walk around with both of these battle
ropes right here once again living fit
uses a polydactron rope which is the
most durable rope that you're going to
find now when it comes to this canvas
rope it looks like they did a triple
strand rope right here which is not as
durable as a braided rope but because
you have this added you know added layer
of protection with the canvas you know
durability should be anything you worry
about this rope is going to be great for
usage outside now with this braided rope
you know since it is braided it takes
longer to make that's a good thing
because it's you know it's going to be
more durable than a triple strand rope
that doesn't have you know a canvas it's
going to last you a really long time now
both of these ropes do have a grip right
here but as you can see they're
different right so that's just because
of the construction of the Rope so with
this canvas rope you can see where you
know you do in fact have that triple
strand it might be pretty nice though
you can fit your fingers kind of in
those grooves and give you a good grip
and that's obviously not the case with
this braided rope but I don't think
that's going to impact you negatively
whatsoever now once again I have the one
and a half inch diameter versions of
these ropes so they both weigh 28 pounds
and these are both 50 feet long as well
all right so I'm gonna show you guys how
to properly set your battle rope up for
your next workout now what a lot of
people like to do is they like taking a
kettlebell and basically what they do is
they just run the Rope through it and
then use this as their anchor now that's
a pretty good option only thing you got
to worry about is that's going to wobble
as you're working out and that's you
know just annoying and that's going to
make things a little bit more difficult
on you so another option is to use you
know a power rack a squat rack anything
that kind of has a post and basically
the same concept you just wrap your rope
around that post but the thing is you
know and the same thing kind of with the
Kettlebell as well is that it's gonna
actually cause your rope to fray and you
definitely don't want that you know it's
going to decrease the lifespan of your
rope so living fit went ahead and tossed
in this strap right here and what I've
done because I'm kind of tight on Space
mode myself
as I tied it around the post right here
on my bumper stacker and then I went
ahead and ran the Rope through it and so
the Rope actually isn't going to be
what's getting messed up it's actually
going to be the strap as I'm working out
and this is moving around sliding around
it's going to wear this down before it
wears down the rope and so basically
once you're all set up you know you got
to make sure that everything is nice and
even it's the same length on both sides
you just grab your ends and you just get
right to it
okay so who should purchase a battle
rope from livingfit well if you're in
the market for a high quality battle
rope I think it's going to be tough to
beat both of these options right here
since they're both 50 feet long there's
some added variety to your workouts and
there's also added variety to your
buying options in the form of
construction weight and diameter
okay so what about the people who might
not want to purchase one of these battle
ropes well let's talk about the length
you know once again they're both 50 feet
long you don't have the option of a
shorter rope and not everybody has that
much space in their home gym so if you
don't I'd probably suggest checking out
some other options out there and you
know the cheapest one here is basically
a hundred bucks and if you don't want to
spend a hundred dollars on a battle rope
you know you can definitely check out
some cheaper options online just
remember they probably won't last you as
long as these will right here and if you
need your battle rope to be a little bit
lighter I'm sure there's some options
out there that you can find
[Music]
that's about all I have for you guys
today on the living fit battle ropes
both of these are a great way to get a
quick cardio workout in while also
building some muscle at the same time I
really like the variety in terms of your
buying with the diameter the weight and
of course the option of a rope with a
canvas for added durability they might
be a little bit expensive for some
people but honestly I think the quality
makes that price tag worth it thanks for
watching y'all I hope this video was
really helpful and I was able to answer
any questions you may have about these
battle ropes as always stay posted for
my next video but for now head over to
barbin.com you can read more about both
of these ropes just search bar Bend
living fit battle rope review our
article is going to pull up and you can
read everything that I talked about here
today I'll see y'all later
thank you